CHAITANYA UTTARWAR

522, Wismer street, Waterloo N2K0E8, Waterloo, ON | (H) 5483336319 | chaitanyauttarwar046@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Seasoned Java developer with more than 2 years of experience in fast-paced agile development. Excellent Programming and research skills. Track record of achieving exceptional results in consuming RESTful services and Automation.

Technical Skills

- **Programming Languages:** Java, C, C++, JavaScript, **Technology:** Spring Framework, Maven, CSS, HTML, PHP
- **Databases:** MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite
- Dialogflow, UiPath, Automation Anywhere
- Tools: Git, Jenkins, Postman, SoapUl, Latex

Experience

Programmer Analyst 09/2017 to 04/2019

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd – Chennai, TN, India

- Contributed to spring framework build in Maven and Jenkins to develop RESTful web services which were to be used by America's leading Investor-owned utility.
- Conducted logical analysis of engineering, and other technical problems. Formulated models of solutions.
- Contributed, deployed and maintained various webservices on Heroku as well as EC2/AWS.
- Developed and tested a chatbot for client website on Dialogflow with webhooks running on google firebase.
- Worked on a chatbot for Facebook messenger with webhooks coded in php and running on Heroku.
- Created an automation tool for internal process on UiPath and Automation Anywhere.
- Achieved a global rank of 12 in an internal competition on Java and was given a title of "Orbit Shifter"

Process Analyst 01/2014 to 04/2014

Ecoad – Pune, Maharashtra

- Designed a Java based inventory system which would keep track of profits and stocks.
- Prepared manuals and trained workers to use new stencils for paper bag manufacturing according to organizational policy.
- Designed and devised new methods which increased the production by 10%

Education

Graduate Certificate, Mobile Solutions Development:

May 2019 - Present

Conestoga College - Waterloo, Ontario

- Coursework related to HTML, CSS, JavaScript and C#
- Scored 3.89 GPA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science:

August 2012 - May 2017

Pune University - Pune, Maharashtra

Graduated in top 5% of the class. (GPA: 3.9/4.0, First Class with Distinction)

Co-curricular Activities

Student Volunteer May 2019

Conestoga College - Waterloo

- Organized and contributed towards various in-house events under student engagement section
- Helped international students for onboarding them on their new semester.

Student Representative May 2019

Conestoga College – Waterloo

- Student representative of my course (Mobile Solutions Development)
- Represented students for their betterment in college and resolved their queries and problems.
- Numerous suggestions given for betterment of campus and surroundings.

Student Technology Squad

December 2013 to August 2016

- Contributed as team leader for Software department of the college ROBOCON 2015 Team.
 - Responsibilities included developing a native code running on Arduino and capable of handling wireless requests and move robot accordingly.
- Facilitated various lectures for freshmen and sophomore students in computer hardware and software focusing mainly on android and embedded systems.
- Conducted workshops under "Train the Teacher" initiative by institute.

Curricular Activities

- Participated in various hackathons while with previous employer, represented my department in the pool of 100+ participants and stood out as an outstanding achiever.
 - Solution proposed An Optimised internal dashboard tool on SpringBoot for managing and testing various webservices at once